<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools for Automation on Ish's Blog</title><link>https://ishabbi.tech/categories/tools-for-automation/</link><description>Recent content in Tools for Automation on Ish's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:55:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ishabbi.tech/categories/tools-for-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fetch GraphQL query from an Apollo client using APQ - Part 2</title><link>https://ishabbi.tech/posts/debug-apq-extension-part2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ishabbi.tech/posts/debug-apq-extension-part2/</guid><description>&lt;style>
 .img-shadow {
 box-shadow: 0 2px 2px 2px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.2);
 }
&lt;/style>
&lt;div style="text-align: justify">
&lt;p>As discussed in &lt;a href="https://ishabbi.tech/posts/debug-apq-extension-part1" >part-1&lt;/a> of this blog, when using apollo client one can boost the performance of the graphql queries by using &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Automatic persisted queries&amp;rdquo; or APQ&lt;/strong>. By using APQ, the server caches each requests initiated from the browser against a hash which if not found, forces the web browser to re-send the request with the complete graphql query.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fetch GraphQL query from an Apollo client using APQ - Part 1</title><link>https://ishabbi.tech/posts/debug-apq-extension-part1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 23:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ishabbi.tech/posts/debug-apq-extension-part1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>APIs (Application Programming Interfaces)&lt;/strong> for web applications have evolved significantly since the early days of the internet. Initially, APIs were simple and used primarily for data exchange between server and client, often through protocols like SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol). These early APIs were cumbersome and required extensive documentation and strict adherence to protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rise of &lt;strong>REST (Representational State Transfer)&lt;/strong> in the early 2000s marked a major shift, offering a more flexible and scalable approach to building web APIs. RESTful APIs leverage standard HTTP methods, making them easier to use and more intuitive. However, 2015 saw a paradigm shift, Facebook (now Meta Inc.) introduced &lt;strong>GraphQL&lt;/strong> to the world, allowing clients to request specific data, resulting to it&amp;rsquo;s rapid adoption amongst enterprises. According to reports, it is projected that by 2025, &lt;em>over 50% of enterprises will use GraphQL in production, up from less than 10% in 2021&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>